<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <link href="http://arxiv.org/api/query?search_query%3Dall%3Aeess.IV%26id_list%3D%26start%3D0%26max_results%3D500" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <title type="html">ArXiv Query: search_query=all:eess.IV&amp;id_list=&amp;start=0&amp;max_results=500</title>
  <id>http://arxiv.org/api/8zhhwuvyvTD4sIxRoWJ8N4dptm0</id>
  <updated>2017-10-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <opensearch:totalResults xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">16</opensearch:totalResults>
  <opensearch:startIndex xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">0</opensearch:startIndex>
  <opensearch:itemsPerPage xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">500</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1709.07875v1</id>
    <updated>2017-09-22T21:56:11Z</updated>
    <published>2017-09-22T21:56:11Z</published>
    <title>Elliptification of Rectangular Imagery</title>
    <summary>  We present and discuss different algorithms for converting rectangular
imagery into elliptical regions. We will focus primarily on methods that use
mathematical mappings with explicit and invertible equations. We will also
present different post-processing effects that could be applied to enhance the
resulting images and minimize distortion.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chamberlain Fong</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">43 pages, 13 figures; PDF only -- not generated from TeX</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1709.07875v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1709.07875v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1709.07745v1</id>
    <updated>2017-09-18T22:55:09Z</updated>
    <published>2017-09-18T22:55:09Z</published>
    <title>Measurement of amplitude of the moiré patterns in digital
  autostereoscopic 3D display</title>
    <summary>  The article presents the experimental measurements of the amplitude of the
moir\'e patterns in a digital autostereoscopic barrier-type 3D display across a
wide angular range with a small increment. The period and orientation of the
moir\'e patterns were also measured as functions of the angle. Simultaneous
branches are observed and analyzed. The theoretical interpretation is also
given. The results can help preventing or minimizing the moir\'e effect in
displays.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Vladimir Saveljev</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Sung-Kyu Kim</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">13 pages, 14 figures, 12 equations</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1709.07745v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1709.07745v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1709.07041v1</id>
    <updated>2017-09-20T19:19:58Z</updated>
    <published>2017-09-20T19:19:58Z</published>
    <title>Image Acquisition System Using On Sensor Compressed Sampling Technique</title>
    <summary>  Advances in CMOS technology have made high resolution image sensors possible.
These image sensor pose significant challenges in terms of the amount of raw
data generated, energy efficiency and frame rate. This paper presents a new
design methodology for an imaging system and a simplified novel pixel design to
be used in such system so that Compressed Sensing technique can be implemented
easily at the sensor level. This results in significant energy savings as it
not only cuts the raw data rate but also reduces transistor count per pixel,
decreases pixel size, increases fill factor, simplifies ADC, JPEG encoder and
JPEG decoder design and decreases wiring as well as address decoder size by
half. Thus Compressed Sensing has the potential to increase the resolution of
image sensors for a given technology and die size while significantly
decreasing the power consumption and design complexity. We show that it has
potential to reduce power consumption by about 23%-65%.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Pravir Singh Gupta</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Gwan Seong Choi</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1709.07041v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1709.07041v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1709.07406v1</id>
    <updated>2017-08-29T21:10:07Z</updated>
    <published>2017-08-29T21:10:07Z</published>
    <title>Having your cake and eating it too: Scripted workflows for image
  manipulation</title>
    <summary>  The reproducibility issue in science has come under increased scrutiny. One
consistent suggestion lies in the use of scripted methods or workflows for data
analysis. Image analysis is one area in science in which little can be done in
scripted methods. The SWIIM Project (Scripted Workflows to Improve Image
Manipulation) is designed to generate workflows from popular image manipulation
tools. In the project, 2 approaches are being taken to construct workflows in
the image analysis area. First, the open-source tool GIMP is being enhanced to
produce an active log (which can be run on a stand-alone basis to perform the
same manipulation). Second, the R system Shiny tool is being used to construct
a graphical user interface (GUI) which works with EBImage code to modify
images, and to produce an active log which can perform the same operations.
This process has been successful to date, but is not complete. The basic method
for each component is discussed, and example code is shown.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Paul A. Thompson</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Norm Matloff</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Fu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ariel Shin</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Written for Work17 Conference</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1709.07406v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1709.07406v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1709.07739v2</id>
    <updated>2017-10-05T07:56:22Z</updated>
    <published>2017-09-22T13:32:49Z</published>
    <title>Single-pixel imaging with Morlet wavelet correlated random patterns</title>
    <summary>  Single-pixel imaging is an indirect imaging technique which utilizes
simplified optical hardware and advanced computational methods. It offers novel
solutions for hyper-spectral imaging, polarimetric imaging, three-dimensional
imaging, holographic imaging, optical encryption and imaging through scattering
media. The main limitations for its use come from relatively high measurement
and reconstruction times. In this paper we propose to reduce the required
signal acquisition time by using a novel sampling scheme based on a random
selection of Morlet wavelets convolved with white noise. While such functions
exhibit random properties, they are locally determined by Morlet wavelet
parameters. The proposed method is equivalent to random sampling of the
properly selected part of the feature space, which maps the measured images
accurately both in the spatial and spatial frequency domains. We compare both
numerically and experimentally the image quality obtained with our sampling
protocol against widely-used sampling with Walsh-Hadamard or noiselet
functions. The results show considerable improvement over the former methods,
enabling single-pixel imaging at low compression rates on the order of a few
percent.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Krzysztof M. Czajkowski</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Anna Pastuszczak</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Rafał Kotyński</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1709.07739v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1709.07739v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1709.09940v2</id>
    <updated>2017-10-03T07:56:14Z</updated>
    <published>2017-09-26T07:13:06Z</published>
    <title>Propagation based phase retrieval using artificial neural networks</title>
    <summary>  Determining the phase of a wave from intensity measurements has many
applications in fields such as electron microscopy, visible light optics, and
medical imaging. Propagation based phase retrieval, where the phase is obtained
from defocused images, has shown significant promise. There are, however,
limitations in the accuracy of the retrieved phase arising from such methods.
Sources of error include shot noise, image misalignment, and diffraction
artifacts. We explore the use of artificial neural networks (ANNs) to improve
the accuracy of propagation based phase retrieval algorithms. We employ a phase
retrieval algorithm based on the transport-of-intensity equation to obtain the
phase from simulated micrographs of procedurally generated specimens. We then
train an ANN with pairs of retrieved and exact phases, and use the trained ANN
to process a test set of retrieved maps. The total error in the phase is
significantly reduced using this method. We also discuss a variety of potential
extensions to this work.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Zachary David Cleary Kemp</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Added references to Rivenson's work on the same topic, which I was
  previously unaware of</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1709.09940v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1709.09940v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.optics" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1710.00532v1</id>
    <updated>2017-10-02T08:46:30Z</updated>
    <published>2017-10-02T08:46:30Z</published>
    <title>Statistically Segregated k-Space Sampling for Accelerating
  Multiple-Acquisition MRI</title>
    <summary>  A central limitation of multiple-acquisition magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)
is the degradation in scan efficiency as the number of distinct datasets grows.
Sparse recovery techniques can alleviate this limitation via randomly
undersampled acquisitions. A frequent sampling strategy is to prescribe for
each acquisition a different random pattern drawn from a common sampling
density. However, naive random patterns often contain gaps or clusters across
the acquisition dimension that in turn can degrade reconstruction quality or
reduce scan efficiency. To address this problem, a statistically-segregated
sampling method is proposed for multiple-acquisition MRI. This method generates
multiple patterns sequentially, while adaptively modifying the sampling density
to minimize k-space overlap across patterns. As a result, it improves
incoherence across acquisitions while still maintaining similar sampling
density across the radial dimension of k-space. Comprehensive simulations and
in vivo results are presented for phase-cycled balanced steady-state free
precession and multi-echo T$_2$-weighted imaging. Segregated sampling achieves
significantly improved quality in both Fourier and compressed-sensing
reconstructions of multiple-acquisition datasets.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>L Kerem Senel</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Toygan Kilic</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alper Gungor</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Emre Kopanoglu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>H Emre Guven</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Emine U Saritas</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Aykut Koc</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tolga Cukur</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">10 pages, 9 figures. Submitted to IEEE Transactions on Medical
  Imaging</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1710.00532v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1710.00532v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1709.06342v1</id>
    <updated>2017-09-19T10:54:24Z</updated>
    <published>2017-09-19T10:54:24Z</published>
    <title>Visual Quality Assessment of Panoramic Video</title>
    <summary>  In contrast with traditional video, panoramic video enables spherical viewing
direction with support for head-mounted displays, providing an interactive and
immersive experience. Unfortunately, to the best of our knowledge, there are
few visual quality assessment (VQA) methods, either subjective or objective,
for panoramic video. This paper proposes both subjective and objective methods
for assessing quality loss in impaired panoramic video. Specifically, we first
establish a new database, which includes the viewing direction data from
several subjects watching panoramic video sequences. Then, from our database,
we find a high consistency in viewing direction across different subjects. The
viewing directions are normally distributed in the center of the front regions,
but they sometimes fall into other regions, related to video content. Given
this finding, we present a subjective VQA method for measuring different mean
opinion score (DMOS) of the whole and regional panoramic video, in terms of
overall DMOS (O-DMOS) and vectorized DMOS (V-DMOS), respectively. Moreover, we
propose two objective VQA methods for panoramic video, in light of human
perception characteristics of panoramic video. One method weighs the distortion
of pixels with regard to their distances to the center of front regions, which
considers human preference in a panorama. The other method predicts viewing
directions according to video content, and then the predicted viewing
directions are leveraged to assign weights to the distortion of each pixel in
our objective VQA method. Finally, our experimental results verify that both
the subjective and objective methods proposed in this paper advance
state-of-the-art VQA for panoramic video.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Mai Xu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Chen Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zulin Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Zhenzhong Chen</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1709.06342v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1709.06342v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1709.07747v2</id>
    <updated>2017-10-02T12:23:41Z</updated>
    <published>2017-09-19T14:23:24Z</published>
    <title>SNR-based adaptive acquisition method for fast Fourier ptychographic
  microscopy</title>
    <summary>  Fourier ptychographic microscopy (FPM) is a computational imaging technique
with both high resolution and large field-of-view. However, the effective
numerical aperture (NA) achievable with a typical LED panel is ambiguous and
usually relies on the repeated tests of different illumination NAs. The imaging
quality of each raw image usually depends on the visual assessments, which is
subjective and inaccurate especially for those dark field images. Moreover, the
acquisition process is really time-consuming.In this paper, we propose a
SNR-based adaptive acquisition method for quantitative evaluation and adaptive
collection of each raw image according to the signal-to-noise ration (SNR)
value, to improve the FPM's acquisition efficiency and automatically obtain the
maximum achievable NA, reducing the time of collection, storage and subsequent
calculation. The widely used EPRY-FPM algorithm is applied without adding any
algorithm complexity and computational burden. The performance has been
demonstrated in both USAF targets and biological samples with different imaging
sensors respectively, which have either Poisson or Gaussian noises model.
Further combined with the sparse LEDs strategy, the number of collection images
can be shorten to around 25 frames while the former needs 361 images, the
reduction ratio can reach over 90%. This method will make FPM more practical
and automatic, and can also be used in different configurations of FPM.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>An Pan</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Yan Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Maosen Li</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Meiling Zhou</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Junwei Min</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ming Lei</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Baoli Yao</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">11 pages, 6 figures</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1709.07747v2" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1709.07747v2" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.optics" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1709.08182v1</id>
    <updated>2017-09-24T11:03:52Z</updated>
    <published>2017-09-24T11:03:52Z</published>
    <title>Neuromorphic adaptive edge-preserving denoising filter</title>
    <summary>  In this paper, we present on-sensor neuromorphic vision hardware
implementation of denoising spatial filter. The mean or median spatial filters
with fixed window shape are known for its denoising ability, however, have the
drawback of blurring the object edges. The effect of blurring increases with an
increase in window size. To preserve the edge information, we propose an
adaptive spatial filter that uses neuron's ability to detect similar pixels and
calculates the mean. The analog input differences of neighborhood pixels are
converted to the chain of pulses with voltage controlled oscillator and applied
as neuron input. When the input pulses charge the neuron to equal or greater
level than its threshold, the neuron will fire, and pixels are identified as
similar. The sequence of the neuron's responses for pixels is stored in the
serial-in-parallel-out shift register. The outputs of shift registers are used
as input to the selector switches of an averaging circuit making this an
adaptive mean operation resulting in an edge preserving mean filter. System
level simulation of the hardware is conducted using 150 images from Caltech
database with added Gaussian noise to test the robustness of edge-preserving
and denoising ability of the proposed filter. Threshold values of the hardware
neuron were adjusted so that the proposed edge-preserving spatial filter
achieves optimal performance in terms of PSNR and MSE, and these results
outperforms that of the conventional mean and median filters.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Aidana Irmanova</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Olga Krestinskaya</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Pappachen James</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">IEEE International Conference on Rebooting Computing 2017</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1709.08182v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1709.08182v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1710.01135v1</id>
    <updated>2017-09-29T20:49:54Z</updated>
    <published>2017-09-29T20:49:54Z</published>
    <title>A Graph Signal Processing View on Functional Brain Imaging</title>
    <summary>  Modern neuroimaging techniques provide us with unique views on brain
structure and function; i.e., how the brain is wired, and where and when
activity takes place. These large datasets contain increasingly rich
information that can be analyzed in terms of network structure to reveal
organizing principles at the systems level. Graph representations are versatile
models where nodes are associated to brain regions and edges to structural or
functional connections. Structural graphs model neural pathways in white matter
that are the anatomical backbone between regions. Functional graphs are built
based on functional connectivity, which is a pairwise measure of statistical
interdependency between activity traces of regions. Therefore, most research to
date has focussed on analyzing these graphs reflecting structure or function.
  Graph signal processing (GSP) is an emerging research theme where signals
recorded at the nodes of the graph are analyzed taking into account the
underlying graph structure. An increasing number of fundamental operations has
been generalized to the graph setting, allowing to analyze the signals from a
new viewpoint. Here, we introduce GSP for functional brain imaging and
demonstrate its potential to integrate brain structure, contained in the graph
itself, with brain function, residing in the graph signals. We show how brain
activity can be meaningfully filtered based on concepts of spectral modes
derived from brain structure. We also derive other operations such as surrogate
data generation or decompositions informed by cognitive systems. In sum, GSP
puts up a novel framework for the analysis of brain imaging data.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Weiyu Huang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Thomas AW Bolton</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Alejandro Ribeiro</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Dimitri Van De Ville</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">Weiyu Huang and Thomas AW Bolton contributed equally</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1710.01135v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1710.01135v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.SI" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1011.3189v5</id>
    <updated>2015-09-26T21:26:34Z</updated>
    <published>2010-11-14T07:53:26Z</published>
    <title>Warping Peirce Quincuncial Panoramas</title>
    <summary>  The Peirce quincuncial projection is a mapping of the surface of a sphere to
the interior of a square. It is a conformal map except for four points on the
equator. These points of non-conformality cause significant artifacts in
photographic applications. In this paper, we propose an algorithm and
user-interface to mitigate these artifacts. Moreover, in order to facilitate an
interactive user-interface, we present a fast algorithm for calculating the
Peirce quincuncial projection of spherical imagery. We then promote the Peirce
quincuncial projection as a viable alternative to the more popular
stereographic projection in some scenarios.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Chamberlain Fong</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Brian K. Vogel</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">updated source code with figures and explanation of the software
  implementation</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1011.3189v5" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1011.3189v5" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.GR" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1709.05937v1</id>
    <updated>2017-09-12T13:21:47Z</updated>
    <published>2017-09-12T13:21:47Z</published>
    <title>Une véritable approche $\ell_0$ pour l'apprentissage de dictionnaire</title>
    <summary>  Sparse representation learning has recently gained a great success in signal
and image processing, thanks to recent advances in dictionary learning. To this
end, the $\ell_0$-norm is often used to control the sparsity level.
Nevertheless, optimization problems based on the $\ell_0$-norm are non-convex
and NP-hard. For these reasons, relaxation techniques have been attracting much
attention of researchers, by priorly targeting approximation solutions (e.g.
$\ell_1$-norm, pursuit strategies). On the contrary, this paper considers the
exact $\ell_0$-norm optimization problem and proves that it can be solved
effectively, despite of its complexity. The proposed method reformulates the
problem as a Mixed-Integer Quadratic Program (MIQP) and gets the global optimal
solution by applying existing optimization software. Because the main
difficulty of this approach is its computational time, two techniques are
introduced that improve the computational speed. Finally, our method is applied
to image denoising which shows its feasibility and relevance compared to the
state-of-the-art.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Yuan Liu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Stéphane Canu</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Paul Honeine</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Su Ruan</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">in French</arxiv:comment>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1709.05937v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1709.05937v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.CV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1710.00965v1</id>
    <updated>2017-10-03T02:45:15Z</updated>
    <published>2017-10-03T02:45:15Z</published>
    <title>Automated and Robust Quantification of Colocalization in Dual-Color
  Fluorescence Microscopy: A Nonparametric Statistical Approach</title>
    <summary>  Colocalization is a powerful tool to study the interactions between
fluorescently labeled molecules in biological fluorescence microscopy. However,
existing techniques for colocalization analysis have not undergone continued
development especially in regards to robust statistical support. In this paper,
we examine two of the most popular quantification techniques for colocalization
and argue that they could be improved upon using ideas from nonparametric
statistics and scan statistics. In particular, we propose a new colocalization
metric that is robust, easily implementable, and optimal in a rigorous
statistical testing framework. Application to several benchmark datasets, as
well as biological examples, further demonstrates the usefulness of the
proposed technique.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Shulei Wang</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ellen T. Arena</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Kevin W. Eliceiri</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ming Yuan</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1710.00965v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1710.00965v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="stat.ME" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="q-bio.QM" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1709.09634v1</id>
    <updated>2017-09-22T21:49:11Z</updated>
    <published>2017-09-22T21:49:11Z</published>
    <title>Real time text localization for Indoor Mobile Robot Navigation</title>
    <summary>  Scene text is an important feature to be extracted, especially in
vision-based mobile robot navigation as many potential landmarks such as
nameplates and information signs contain text. In this paper, a novel two-step
text localization method for Indoor Mobile Robot Navigation is introduced. This
method is based on morphological operators and machine learning techniques and
can be used in real time environments. The proposed method has two steps. At
First, a new set of morphological operators is applied with a particular
sequence to extract high contrast areas that have high probability of text
existence. Using of morphological operators has many advantages such as: high
computation speed, being invariant to several geometrical transformations like
translation, rotations, and scaling, and being able to extract all areas
containing text. After extracting text candidate regions, a set of nine
features are extracted for accurate detection and deletion of the regions that
don't have text. These features are descriptors for texture properties and are
computed in real time. Then, we use a SVM classifier to detect the existence of
text in the region. Performance of the proposed algorithm is compared against a
number of widely used text localization algorithms and the results show that
this method can quickly and effectively localize and extract text regions from
real scenes and can be used in mobile robot navigation under an indoor
environment to detect text based landmarks.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Kazem Qazanfari</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Saeed Shiri</name>
    </author>
    <arxiv:comment xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">5 pages</arxiv:comment>
    <arxiv:journal_ref xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom">IR Open Robocup Symposium, 7-9 April 2010</arxiv:journal_ref>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1709.09634v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1709.09634v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cs.RO" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://arxiv.org/abs/1710.02051v1</id>
    <updated>2017-10-04T13:43:50Z</updated>
    <published>2017-10-04T13:43:50Z</published>
    <title>Stochastic model for the 3D microstructure of pristine and cyclically
  aged cathodes in Li-ion batteries</title>
    <summary>  It is well-known that the microstructure of electrodes in lithium-ion
batteries strongly affects their performance. Vice versa, the microstructure
can exhibit strong changes during the usage of the battery due to aging
effects. For a better understanding of these effects, mathematical analysis and
modeling has turned out to be of great help. In particular, stochastic 3D
microstructure models have proven to be a powerful and very flexible tool to
generate various kinds of particle-based structures. Recently, such models have
been proposed for the microstructure of anodes in lithium-ion energy and power
cells. In the present paper, we describe a stochastic modeling approach for the
3D microstructure of cathodes in a lithium-ion energy cell, which differs
significantly from the one observed in anodes. The model for the cathode data
enhances the ideas of the anode models, which have been developed so far. It is
calibrated using 3D tomographic image data from pristine as well as two aged
cathodes. A validation based on morphological image characteristics shows that
the model is able to realistically describe both, the microstructure of
pristine and aged cathodes. Thus, we conclude that the model is suitable to
generate virtual, but realistic microstructures of lithium-ion cathodes.
</summary>
    <author>
      <name>Klaus Kuchler</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Daniel Westhoff</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Julian Feinauer</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Tim Mitsch</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Ingo Manke</name>
    </author>
    <author>
      <name>Volker Schmidt</name>
    </author>
    <link href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1710.02051v1" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <link title="pdf" href="http://arxiv.org/pdf/1710.02051v1" rel="related" type="application/pdf"/>
    <arxiv:primary_category xmlns:arxiv="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom" term="cond-mat.mtrl-sci" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="cond-mat.mtrl-sci" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="eess.IV" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
    <category term="physics.app-ph" scheme="http://arxiv.org/schemas/atom"/>
  </entry>
</feed>
